Uh, my name is Drew. I am the head
[music] of product and AI at Tessle. Uh,
for those of you who don't know, Tessle
is an agent enablement platform. We
recently launched sort of publicly to
everybody. So, you can try it now.
Everything's free of charge. Just go
sign up. Uh very quickly I'll tell you
what it is and then the whole demo is
going to be me showing how we use
Tessle. So
uh when we say agent enablement platform
what does that really mean? Uh probably
the simplest way you can think of it is
a tool to do uh context engineering at
scale in a team in an organization
across a community. And so the idea
behind this is like the core thing that
we're building is a registry for
context. So you can think of this as
like in its most reductive sense uh mpm
for markdown files right so it's a way
of uh the things we want to help you
with is creating context right so a lot
of times we find when people want to
start using agents they find there's
this 5 to 10 year backlog of information
about their organizational setting right
like u style guides security policies
documentation on the APIs and tools that
are like internal to the team. Um, all
these things that agents don't know
about, they can't know about because
it's your internal information. Um,
there's also things like, oh, we use
this old version of some open source
dependency that hasn't been mainlined
for six years. The agent's been trained
on the later versions. They're always
making mistakes, right? Like your stack,
basically. Uh, and so the first thing
that Tesla wants to do is help you
onboard all of that knowledge into a
sort of agentfriendly format. Um, we
have ambitions obviously to be like
everything like you could connect your
notion, you could connect Google Docs,
you could look through historical PRs
and we'll figure out what your style
guide is based on frequent comments that
you give. That's obviously like the
direction we're going over time. Right
now, this creation experience is focused
on uh platform framework uh like
internal APIs that you might own. We
will help you create documentation for
it. So say you've got a a library
everybody uses at your company. We'll
you'll hook up your GitHub. We'll
generate documentation for it and then
we can help you keep it up to date as
you update the uh the library itself
with new PRs.
On top of that then so that's the the
creation process. So you you now have
this markdown this context that's
supposed to make agents more effective.
Does it like does it actually help? And
so the sort of next pillar that Tesla is
building out is a way to evaluate
context that you've written specifically
for your use case. Right? So the idea
that you have a library, you have people
internally, maybe externally, right?
Maybe you have an SDK that uh other
people are using publicly. You want to
know does cursor use it better than
claude? Does codeex like fail on this
particular API? So we help you generate
uh coding challenges essentially related
to using your library. Uh and then we
have harnesses where we can run all of
the agents through it and we can report
to you uh these are the parts of your
library that aren't working well. These
are the parts that are that are working
well. Uh here's how much better it gets
when you add this context or if you
create a new version of the context we
can tell [clears throat] you like did
you see a performance improvement or
not. So that's the evaluation.
Now ideally you say okay I've created
this context it works I want to roll it
out and so distribution which is
something I'm going to show here today
that's sort of the core thing in the
product uh that's ready for prime time
ready for everybody to use uh that is
the part that's like a registry right so
you have a way to publish your
documentation and then install it into
projects and repositories you have all
the sort of versioning you'd come to
expect with a registry I can explain why
that's cool and valuable uh and then
once you But you also have ways to sort
of monitor and say okay who has adopted
it who hasn't uh like have people
adopted the latest version? Uh you can
do like a dependabot style sort of add
the knowledge to people's downstream
libraries. They can just accept a PR and
be off and running. Uh and then the
final pillar
optimization. This is like once you've
deployed it, it's in the wild. We want
to help you understand through your
agent logs and things like that where
are people hitting problems and then
automatically sort of have a feedback
loop where we're fixing and improving
the context or maybe even suggesting new
context uh to make agents more effective
and give you insight into where are
people failing with agents today. That's
kind of the Tesla platform. Like I said,
a lot of that is future vision. If
you're interested and excited, we're
looking for design partners, early
access. So please get in touch if you
want to help sort of build out the full
vision. But today I will show you all
what exists in the product that you
could go download and try today. So
okay, without further ado, I'm going to
be building a to-do app that just runs
on the CLI. Just a simple example to
show a lot of the things I mentioned.
I'm going to kick something off because
uh I am taunting the demo gods today. I
am both doing everything live. I am also
running on uh our basically tip of tree
which is already auto updated four times
today. So hopefully uh everything works.
Please have forbearance but I always
find these demos much more fun if they
uh are real. So to start off uh I'm
going to so I'm going to start in this
empty uh to-do CLI. You can see here I
have nothing except for an environment
variable that has keys for uh open AI
that I will not open because I don't
want you all to see them. Uh and then
also a get ignore but otherwise empty.
So the first thing I'm going to do is
I'm going to run
let's see I'm going to run tessle
install
and then I'm actually going to install
>> I can is this better for folks? Is this
>> better? Okay. Um, so this is Tessle
Engineering's internal style guide for
Python. So I mentioned you have uh
library documentation, but you can
really do anything that you would pass
as context to an agent. You can publish
it to the Tessle registry. So our our
core use case is library teams, but it
sort of works for anything. So you'll
see here I'm going to install the Python
uh the Python style guide, and you'll
see a few things have happened as I've
done this. Uh first is that we have gone
ahead and set up it says I'm
authenticated. We've set up some
integrations with agents that we can
already detect that you're using. So in
this case I'm a big cursor and claude
code user. So we've created an agents
MD. We've created a cloud MD. Uh and
then we've also set up an MCP.
This MCP all it does is set up so that
Tessle can be run.
Uh and then in addition to the MCP we've
added this Tessle JSON. So you'll see
here and this is like one of the first
key concepts. We believe that context
that you're using in your repository
should as it moves closer and closer to
code start to have a life cycle that
looks more and more like code. Right? So
the idea being here this is my style
guide for Python. It's version 0.2. Uh
if somebody comes in and says like oh
major revamp we've changed the way we're
doing Python. I'm bumping the version to
1.0 or you know 0.1. I don't want to
come in on a Monday morning and be like,
"Oh, I thought I was going to ship
features, but I guess today I'm
migrating everything to the new style
guide so that you know my context will
stop complaining at me." So, I just
won't bump the version yet. Right? It
gives you that control so that you can
stay pinned to the knowledge that you
have been building for, but it also
gives somebody on the other side
visibility into okay, who has updated or
not updated to version 0.1, right? And
maybe this one is in maintenance mode,
so we just don't think it's worth the
effort. So, we'll leave it pinned to
0.0.
But, you know, it we have the ability,
we have that control. Uh, and you'll see
as we get into libraries and packages
where this is like especially powerful,
but we think that this is like a thing
that you should be doing with a lot of
your context is explicitly declaring it
as dependencies, being able to control
and version it as you work. Uh, and so
then you'll see also within this tessle
folder, we've installed our first couple
tiles. So a tile is just a tessle
package. It's like a Ruby gem or a Rust
crate. Everybody has to have a name for
their thing. So ours is a tile. It has
no meaning other than a tessle package.
So if you look in here, I just installed
the Python package. And you can see it's
markdown files, right? There's nothing
special about it. It's just context that
you want for your agent. Uh in this
case, I've set up some things like, oh,
I want you to use UV as the package
manager. If I come in here for project
setup, very standard. I've said things
like uh I don't know if you all have
seen this, but agents love to write
package manifests themselves instead of
using the tool to create them. They just
hallucinate dependencies and then
install them. Uh so I say like you can't
do that. You must use UV, right? Like
this is all just sort of standard stuff.
Uh I do this in every Python project. So
now I have a way of sort of making that
uniform uh everywhere I go. I'm just
going to move this over here. So I've
just installed that. That's all I've
done. Uh, and now I'm going to go over
to I have some prompts pre-written just
so I don't have to type them,
but I'll move over. So, in this case,
all I'm doing I'm creating a CLI app.
Uh, it has I'm asking it to use my
standard Python setup. So, that thing I
just installed, it's going to have two
commands. To-do add task adds a to-do to
like a global SQLite database. And then
to-do list will show all of the commands
with arrow key navigation. Uh and then I
ask it to use typer and prompt toolkit
to uh manage the CLI itself.
So I'll go ahead. Oh god, why did it go
into plan mode? Uh ask before edits run.
Okay. So as this is running, I'll sort
of vamp a bit on the next steps. But
before I go, I'm just going to to try
and cover the the time it runs. Any
questions just to start off? Anything
folks want to ask about?
What's up?
>> Sort of the conventions that you use.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Right.
>> Yes. So that tile that I installed, that
tesslege/python
is where we've said things like UV is
the package manager of choice. Use pym
to set your dependencies.
Um, install dependencies a certain way.
You'll probably notice Oh. Oh god, good.
I'm glad I you can tell it's fresh
because none of the permissions are are
accepted. Um, so you'll see here it is
sort of following these things. It's
using UV add. Uh, one thing that I
didn't show in here, we'll see if it
follows along. It's creating the
database schema. Uh, let's see if we can
find it.
Um,
yeah. So, it's checking the project
setup. It's reading Tesla JSON to see
what might be installed. And then it is
running UVNIT and sort of going through
the the request that I made. Um, we'll
see here that it's adding typer and
prompt toolkit. Those were the commands
that I asked for. So next up while this
is running uh yes don't ask again uh I
can go in here and I can say tessle
uh tessle search typer.
So in this case the next part I talked
about you have your private repos but
then you also might have a public
repository or public dependency that
you're using in this case typer. Uh and
so I can look through here and say ah
okay there's typer there's typer cli
uh I want typer so I'll install that
that adds documentation for uh my my
agent to use I can do the same thing uh
tessle install prompt toolkit
and so in this case oh not tessle
installed tessle sorry tessle search um
in this case tessle has gone out and
created uh prompt toolkit
documentation for 10,000 open source
libraries that you can just use sort of
versioned appropriately. If there's a
version you want to use or a library you
want to use that we don't have, there's
a request form we can sort of get that
uh created for you. Uh so in this case
uh I will assume it used the latest.
I'll just go ahead and do that. So I've
added this documentation. Uh it is now
working. So let's we'll see if that if
it actually succeeded. This is always
the fun part. Um, but this is like a
good example of you can install best
practices, things that you just want to
use in every project. You can also
install your dependencies.
If you have an existing project, when
you run Tesla in it, we will scan your
package JSON or your uh whatever package
manif manifest depending on your
language and we will automatically
search and recommend installing any open
source tiles we have. So, it's a great
way to bootstrap if you already have an
existing project.
So, it claims it's gone ahead and done
the thing. Go ahead and ask your
question.
>> Yeah.
>> That's a great question. I think that
kind of like deeply nested.
What we would recommend is navigate to
each folder to run the sync. Um, in in
theory, there shouldn't be anything
about a monor repo that stops it from
working, but I don't think we
necessarily can discover at any location
multiple package JSONs. Um, if you want
to catch me afterwards, we may talk a
little bit more about uh the use case.
So there is I think there's an
interesting thing of uh we don't
necessarily have great support yet for
if you've got a consumer library with
many languages in it that all have like
you can have one Tesla JSON that just
lists all of it. There'll be a little
bit of a bleed though where when the
agent searches it'll be searching across
documentation for all the languages.
That's something we'd love to add
support for like a cleaner
differentiation.
>> Any more questions or
Okay, good.
>> Okay. So it claims to me that I can run
uv run to-do add
write. Let's just say um give awesome
demo. Uh so let's see. Let's see if it
works. All right. So it says it has it
has worked. And then if I go ahead and
do uvun to-do list.
Oh my god, I love when a demo works. Uh
so there's keyboard navigation. I think
these were some that it added while it
was testing its solution. I can hit
enter to toggle something is done. Uh
and then I can escape to exit. Awesome.
So, it worked. Uh you'll notice here
that there are no due dates. I just
everything I guess is always urgent.
It's always happening. Uh I'd love to
add a natural language due date
extraction field. So, I can just type
like do this tomorrow or do this some
other time. Uh so, I have a library for
that somewhere. Uh this is called NL
dates. This is just a little library I
put together. All this does is take in a
string that is assuming like is assumed
to contain a natural language date
string and it returns a date that you
can use in your code. Uh and you'll
notice here that in this uh in this
library I've written some documentation.
So when I say I wrote it, I asked cloud
code to write it, right? Like this is
also a thing that tessle can generate
for you. But what I wanted to emphasize
here is you don't have to. This isn't
like a proprietary secret thing that
Tesla creates. It's just markdown files.
If you already have some that exist,
you're welcome to start from there. We
can also help you create it. You can
edit it afterwards. Like very open, very
flexible. So, I have some documentation
here on how do you install this because
I didn't want to publish it to Pi. So,
it's just on my GitHub. Uh how do you
need to create and like get things set
up. The only thing that's special here
is a tile.json. And you can think of
this as the manifest that you're going
to use to publish to the registry. So in
this case, it's version 0.0.4.
Uh I've said that this documentation is
describing this version of the library.
So this is just a standard package URL.
Uh has the version string at the end. Uh
and then I give it a link to like
where's the entry point to the
documentation. This could be named
anything. Doesn't have to be index.mmd.
Uh you could name it fu.mmd and that
would be fine. Uh this will uh when I
run tessle tile publish docs. I'm not
going to do it because I've already done
it. Um but you'll notice here docs is
just the name of the folder it's in,
right? That contains a tile json. It's
all very flexible. You can sort of do
what you'd like. Uh once I publish this
though, now first I will show you this
is the tessle registry. So you can see
here this hopefully looks very familiar
right like mpm pi pi it's just a place
you can see things in this case this is
a private uh tile so this is the library
I'm not asking other people to use I
just want to use it personally uh you
can see we've published it here it's
just a markdown file so now I can go
over to my to-do CLI and I can do tessle
uh I'll just do search so you can see
it. So I'll do Tessle search and then DF
ball is my personal account and then uh
NL dates.
So this is funny. There is a version
1.2.4 because somebody took my demo
machine back in the other room and
published a random version. So there's
no actual 1.2.4. Uh but there is a
0.0.4.
Uh I can go ahead and install this. It's
going to bring it in. You'll see. Okay.
Now there's a new tile uh index nmd with
a tile JSON.
Couple things like we put these files in
your repository because we wanted it to
be um first a level of redundancy. If
there's ever a moment when like Tesla is
down, we don't want you to lose the docs
so that you can be keep writing code. So
your agent can always GP over the the
file base. It also lets you build tools
on top of the documentation if you'd
like. But the main way we would
recommend using it is we also have
installed an MCP server that it's a bit
faster. It's a bit more accurate. So
it's a better way to find it. But what
we found is to make these things really
reliable. It's good to have many layers
of redundancy and fail safe. So just
giving it many ways to find the context
it needs just leads to a higher success
rate. So I have installed the uh the
documentation on my private library. So
this is something uh unless OpenAI is
training on my personal GitHub today uh
it knows nothing about. So I'll come
over here and the next thing we're going
to ask for is
uh check the docs for NL dates and see
how to install it. Uh because like I
said it's pulling it not from pi. It's
actually just pulling it from a git URL.
Uh and then I want it to add support for
pulling out natural language
descriptions.
uh and it needs to make sure to add a
due date. So in this case, I'm being a
little more prescriptive of like check
the docs and stuff. You don't actually
have to do this. We've added steering
into agents to get it to call, but just
to try and tame the demo gods a little
bit. I'm being uh more prescriptive and
you can always say something like use
tessle and you'll get like near 100%
activation, but we try to make it a
little simpler and more ergonomic. So
you shouldn't have to write that. Uh but
I only tempt fate so much. Um so this is
going while this is running. Maybe I'll
pause again if folks have any questions
on what I've just shown.
>> So the steering is just limited to
dispatch to tle as you add components.
It does as you add add more tiles. It
doesn't require any updates to the
agents or claw or whatever. It's just if
you add a new like codeex or whatever
the next one is, you would just add
another whatever MD.
>> That's right. That's right. So whenever
and this is a thing that we've tried to
do is make it on the consumption side
really really seamless like you don't
have to do anything. Uh so ideally
somebody might you know like the
equivalent of mpm installed they might
add the knowledge but then everybody in
the repo you know just gets it right
they have access to the MCP server as
long as they've installed tessle you
don't have to like keep reyncing your
dependencies or anything like that. Um
if I show you here what uh agents MD
looks like. So this was autopop
populated when I ran tesla init. All it
does is it points to this tessle
rules.mmd
which has uh so when you have a tile
there's basically two kinds of context
you can add there is uh documentation
and this is passive things that the
agent has to ask for right so that's
it'll go through the mcp or it can grap
through the files and then we have rules
which are similar like a cursor rules or
you know something you might put in your
cloud MD which are proactively
registered that say like you must do a
certain thing a certain way. So in this
case, we have a uh you'll see like my
Python rules are here. They're at
imported into agents MD and if you like
keep following these links, you'll see
okay, we get all the way in and it is
just that tile that I showed you all,
right? Like here is my best practices
for running Python. I want it to always
see that. So that has been installed.
You might get more and more of those as
you add tiles, but it's all handled
automatically.
Okay. So, with that in mind, any other
questions before I keep going?
Okay. Uh, so let's see how's it doing.
All right. It is
perfect. The migration worked
supposedly. Um, Claude also says I'm
absolutely right all of the time and
that can't be true. So,
>> so that's still spinning. Um,
>> one question the relationship between
um, you know, the models actually
following these, right? Yeah.
>> Um, so what's what's the gut feel? Do
you do you have like a limited amount of
models that are likely to succeed and
actually do what they're told here? Like
how does it go?
>> Uh, it's a great question and this is my
most rigorous answer to this is like
this is where those eval talked about
come in. So uh this is a feature we're
actively building right now. It should
be available quite soon. When you upload
context to Tessle, we'll optionally
allow you to create evaluation scenarios
and we can run them against all the most
popular agents to give you sort of like
hard numbers against that information.
And then just like the documentation
that we've created, the evaluation
scenarios are like coding tasks that
we're going to run plus grading criteria
that we're going to check. That's all
still files that you can pull into your
repo that you can edit, you can sort of
build on, you can add more and then push
back and continue to like get the
evaluation results. And so my real
answer would say take your context,
evaluate it and then go from there. Now
my gut feel from what we see internally
u most agents are pretty good right like
cursor, cloud code, codeex are all
you're going to get pretty good results.
Uh in our testing, cloud code comes out
usually to be the most respectful of
whatever context you've given it. Uh
cursor can be a little more orary. It
likes to not call tools and maybe needs
a little more explicit uh proddding, but
nothing serious, right? Like you'll get
pretty good results. I'd say 80% plus on
most things if it's sort of clearly
stated and you know, not a lot of
conflicting requirements. Uh did that
answer your question?
Yeah, I mean um what what I'm uh driving
from this is that you're sort of doing
like a agentic evaluation because you're
answering more about like the agent
that's in use and the models they're
using underneath of it. Sounds like
right as the abstraction
>> a little of both. Uh so when we run our
evals we can run them against different
agent harnesses and against different
underlying foundation models. So you
could be like claude code using 45
versus 41 or cursor using open AAI
versus uh anthropic models. So you can
you can do all of that. Yeah. Um okay.
So it says it's done. So let's go ahead
and check it. So I now should be able to
add natural language to my thing. So, I
say uv run to-do add um finish the demo
before Saturday.
Uh oh, and added a task. That was
suspiciously fast. Let's see. Um UV run
to-do list.
Uh finish report. Let's see. Finish the
demo before Saturday. That doesn't look
good. There's no to-doate there. So,
let's go ahead. This is the live part. I
will just say I ran a command and don't
see uh do date extracted.
See what it says. Uh okay. So, as that's
running, I will start to prepare the
next part which is okay. Um
well, now it's working. Well, we'll see.
Uh well, it figures that out. Um one
thing you may have noticed, right? Like
it will pull out a date, but two
problems. The first is that uh it
doesn't strip the date uh knowledge out
of the task itself, right? Like my task
is now do a thing by tomorrow. Um
oh, I think I see I see. Okay.
Are you using
dates to process
the
okay? Um it doesn't pull out that uh
that task string. It also uh will assign
a date for everything, right? So even if
you just say buy groceries, it'll put a
date on it because it is uh okay. Yeah,
this is great. You can see it. It's like
how do I use these things as it goes?
Um, but if I come back over to my uh NL
dates library, I'm realizing I want to
change how it works, right? Like I want
to say instead of calculating a date
from a string, I want it to extract the
date from the string. So take out all of
the date related words and then return a
date plus the rewritten name uh task and
then optionally return none if there's
no date.
So, I have a prompt written for that.
So, it's going to do a few things. Uh,
and I haven't tested this one. We're
going into uncharted territory because I
had the idea for this right before the
session. So, uh, it's going to replace
calculate date with extract date. Uh,
and then it's going to give a rewritten
task and extracted date. And then what
I'm going to do is ask it to update the
docs, bump the version of the library,
and bump the version in the tile JSON.
Right? So,
God help me. Uh, and then let's see if
this has figured it out. Oh. Um, what
this is going to do is it's going to
obviously it's going to add that
feature. It's a breaking change to the
library. Uh, I want to publish the new
docs in the new library, but I don't
want it to break my existing
uh my existing library until I update.
So this is a great example where when
you publish it, you publish a different
version. Uh and then when you say
upgrade to uh NL dates version 0.2, you
can run Tessle uh sync to sort of
install, oh, we've detected you've moved
up a version, so we'll also pull the new
tile version in. Um it gives you control
over that. We've tried to design it so
it's easy to do in CI. So, for example,
you could have a CI hook in your library
that says, "Hey, anytime you merge to
main, check if the docs have changed,
bump the version, and republish." So,
it's very easy to make this just a
seamless part of your publishing flow.
Uh, I won't do that here. That was a
little beyond the realm of a quick demo.
Um, see if this is working. We can also,
this is the most fun part for me of
doing vibe coding is like having
multiple sessions and feeling like I
have this swarm of developers behind me.
Uh, okay. It's updating. We'll see how
that works.
It is also updating here. That looked um
delightfully slow. So, I think it is now
using the LM uh as this is finishing up.
Any questions on what I just showed? Go
ahead.
>> So, like one of the calls that I did
earlier.
>> Yes. Yeah. So you mentioned like the
redundancy earlier, but is there a way
to tell like if it's using the local
markdown versus
>> uh great question. So the search itself
if it calls MCP tool that is running
locally. Uh and then we we are probably
going to add support to just run
everything in the cloud if you just want
to have access to like more parallelism
and stuff like that. But it's all
running locally currently. it will you
can think of those files on the disk
almost like a cache where it pulls it
down so you're not making network hops
as you're as you're running uh and then
if it doesn't call the MCP tool that's
when you know it's just like grepping on
its own and looking for things. Did I
answer your question?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Uh all right. Let's see if this
worked.
So, u run to-do add
um finish demo before Sunday
and see. Okay, nice and slow. Nice and
slow. Uh 1123. I think that's right.
Seems right. UV run to-do list.
Uh oh, wow. It even added a new I is
hasn't done that before. the giving me a
nice do in six days instead of just due
on a on a certain day. So that's great.
It extracted
finish report.
Oh, this is interesting. How is it?
It looks like Oh, that's so funny. It
implemented the feature I wanted on top
of NL dates. That's Well, it's a good
thing the fe the feature works. So, uh,
what I will go ahead and do is I'll let
this finish and then I'll ask it to
migrate that code to use the new NL
dates version. Um, but that's nice. This
is actually a good example of why it's
it's good to have documentation because
I'm sure you all have known or have
noticed agents love to reimplement
things, especially if they're simple
enough that it can it can do it. Um,
so I will go ahead. We'll watch this as
it's finishing.
Um,
I'll open up questions again if anybody
has them.
>> I think we're finishing off.
>> We're finishing off. Okay. Uh, I will
very quickly then just show you all the
way this would work. So, if I bring this
up, I would say uh let me bring
if I go into the docs. I go into the
tile JSON. So, if we look here, if I
wanted to publish a new version, I would
say okay, this is going to be version
0.2. Uh they don't these don't have to
be linked. They just are because I
started doing the docs at the same time.
Um but I could say NL dates is now going
to be say 0.3. I've bumped the version
or it could be 1.0. This would just be
whatever is in my pi project. TOML
publish it. And then what I do is I
would uh so I come over here and do
tessle tile publish docs uh which is
whatever updates I'd made. You could
again run this command in CI. And then
uh over here what I would do is I'd say
tessle
tile update and that will look through
for new versions. In this case it
wouldn't do anything because I haven't
updated the package. So first I'd do uv
pip install update the package and then
when I run sync it would update. We're
at time so I'll end here but I promise
it would totally work.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. Thank you. [applause]
[music]